Hossein Afsharipour

Tel: (+44)7514792371 • Email: afsharipourh@gmail.com

Address: 58, Millpoint, Rowditch Place, Derby, UK. DE22 3LR

An experienced petroleum engineer with 4 years of cross-functional experience in the engineering and automotive manufacturing domain with roles in commercial project management. In possession of strong communication and leadership skills due to professional experience as a supervisor in the business and production planning department.

EXPERIENCE

Oxfam / Volunteer

Sep 2019 - Present, Derby, UK.

Kerman Motor Company / Supervisor of Internal and International Claims Management, PRD and Commercial Project Management

Jul 2016 - Apr 2019, Bam, Iran.

Achievements:

- Successfully reached a 70% reduction on supply chain and production loss in two years.
- Successfully claimed 68944 parts from international suppliers (April 2018 to April 2019)
- Supervisor of the year award in 2018.

Memberships:

- Member of the energy management and optimization committee (Jan 2019 Apr 2019)
- Member of internal trainers in HR training department:
 - o Business English communication skills trainer (Mar 2018 Jul 2018)
 - Manufacturing waste control trainer (October 2017- Nov 2017)

Kerman Motor Company / Associated Claims Management Engineer

Aug 2015 - Jul 2016, Bam, Kerman, Iran.

EDUCATION

Azad University of Omidiyeh / Masters of Science

Petroleum Engineering

Feb 2009 - Feb 2013, Omidiyeh, Iran.

Azad University of Kerman / Bachelor of Science

Mining Engineering

Sep 2005 - Sep 2009, Kerman, Iran.

GENERAL SKILLS

Team leadership, Team-working, Verbal and written communication, Problem-solving, Planning, Scheduling, Working to deadlines, Flexibility, Numerical analysis, Ability to work under pressure, Presentation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- MS EXCEL
- MS Powerpoint
- Microsoft Project
- Primavera P6

- Geophysics
- Production Engineering
- Project Management
- Hydraulic Fracturing

LANGUAGE SKILLS

English: FluentPersian: Fluent

Arabic: Advanced LevelItalian: Intermediate

CERTIFICATIONS

Level I Programme / IWCF

Mar 2020

Become a Project Manager / LinkedIn

Aug 2020

Microsoft Project 2019 and Project Online

Desktop / Project Management Institute (PMI)

Aug 2020

Project Management Foundation / Project

Management Institute (PMI)

Aug 2020

Become a Supply Chain Manager / LinkedIn

Aug 2020

Leading Project / Project Management

Institute (PMI)

Aug 2020

Lean Six Sigma Foundation / Project

Management Institute (PMI)

Jul 2020

Process Improvement Foundations / Project

Management Institute (PMI)

Jul 2020

Project Governance and Project

Management Office (PMO) / The Open

University

Jul 2020

Project management: the start of the

project journey / The Open University

Jun 2020

Project Online Reporting with Power BI /

Project Management Institute (PMI)

Jun 2020

Assessing and Improving Strategic Plans /

Project Management Institute (PMI)

Aug 2019

Business Development Foundations /

Project Management Institute (PMI)

Jul 2019

Problem Solving Techniques / Project

Management Institute (PMI)

Jul 2019

Principles of Advanced Management /

Mollasadra Abushahr Educational Group

Jul 2018

PMBOK (Project Management Body of

Knowledge) / Mollasadra Abushahr

Educational Group

Jun 2019

Principles of International Trade and

Business / Industrial Management Institute

Aug 2017

International Commercial Negotiation

Principles and Technologies / TUV NORD

Oct 2016

Claims Management / Industrial Management

Institute

September 2016

Principles and Basics of International Trade and Commerce / TUV NORD

Aug 2016